翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Using an SLList is pretty simple.
SLList 非常易用
You want to add or remove stuff, get stuff, whatever,
你可以添加、删除、获取其中的值
you should use the methods that are provided by the class.
你应该使用类提供的方法
However, technically, the way Java syntax works,
然而，就 Java 语法来讲
you can try and do weird stuff.
你可以试着做些奇怪的事情
So for example, I can reach directly inside of the object and I could say, hey, you know what?
比如直接访问对象内部
L, I'm not going to use your method.
我不会使用 L 的方法
Instead, I'm going to say, take first.next.next
而是调用 first.next.next
and set it equal to L.first.next,
并将其设置为 L
and that can basically do bizarre things to my data structures that are not intended or allowed by the methods provided.
这些对数据结构所做的奇怪的事情，都不是类的方法提供或者允许的
You might consider pausing and guessing what's going to happen in this picture.
暂停一下，猜猜这张图片里会发生什么
So what happens is this right here.
会变成这样
It ends up pointing back at itself and we ruin the list.
它最终指向自己，这个 List 就毁了
This is not something that an IntList or an IntList-like object should do.
这不是 IntList 或类似 IntList 的对象应该做的事情
It shouldn't have an infinite loop.
它不应该有无限循环
I guess this would be the list that's like the number 10
List 的这个节点是10
and then an infinite number of 15s.
然后是无数个15
And that's not something we really intended to support with the methods provided.
我们并不打算提供方法来支持这一点
So we could leave a little note somewhere in the file.
我们可以在文件的某个地方留个小纸条
We could in comments do something like,
可以做一些这样的注释
it is incredibly important--
这是非常重要的...
up here.
在这上面
Note, please do not mess with first.
注意，请不要先弄乱 first
We could do something like that
我们可以这样做
and hope that other programs will look at it,
并希望其他程序也会关注它
but other programmers will probably not.
但其他程序员可能不会在意
And so, instead, Java provides us with a feature
所以 Java 为我们提供了一个特性
where, instead of declaring a member of a class public, we can instead say private.
对于 public 的成员变量，我们可以将它私有化
So I'll just go in here, and I'll say private here.
将这里改为 private
And that does what I want to accomplish.
这就是我想要实现的
Now, the nice thing is, not only is this self-documenting,
这样不仅仅是自我记录
but it's also enforced by the compiler.
编译器也强制执行
If I make this private and then in another class
如果把它设为 private， 然后在另一个类中
I do something like L.first.next.next equals L.first.next,
做 L.first.next.next = L.first.next 这样的事
when I try and compile that file,
编译文件时
I get back that first have private access.
会报错“first 私有访问”
So what the private keyword does is it prevents code in other classes
private 关键字的作用是防止其它类中的代码
from using members-- that is, variables, methods, or constructors--
使用本类中的成员，也就是变量、方法或构造函数等
what private does is it says you cannot use those from outside the SLList class.
private 告诉你不能从 SLList 类外部使用它们
Now, if I had a main method down here in SLList that did funny things like that
如果 SLList 内部有一个 main 方法
it would work fine because it's part of the SLList class,
它会正常工作，因为它是 SLList 类的一部分
but anybody outside-- anybody not editing SLList.java--
但是在 SLList.java 以外
could not access first.
无法访问 first
Now, that's not 100% true.
这并不完全正确
There is a funny feature in Java known as reflection which allows you to bypass these modifiers,
Java 中有一个称为反射的特性，允许绕过这些修饰符
but you rarely, rarely use it.
但是这非常非常少用
And what this does it says, if you're a casual programmer,
private 是说，如果你是个散漫的程序员
this is something you shouldn't mess with
你不应该弄乱这些东西
and the compiler will stop you from doing it.
编译器会阻止你弄乱
So why do we do that?
为什么要这么做呢？
What's the point of restricting access other than the implicit picture I've presented so far?
除了到目前为止所展示的隐式图景之外，限制访问还有什么意义呢？
Well, the basic idea if I wanted to summarize really the heart of private
我来总结一下 private 的核心思想
is to hide implementation details from the users of your class.
用来对用户隐藏类的实现细节
The user doesn't need to know that we have a first variable.
用户不需要知道我们有 first 变量
They shouldn't be messing with it.
他们不应该弄乱它
So by making it private, it's a detail that we the programmer of SLList need but the user does not.
将它设为 private，这是我们 SLList 程序员需要的细节，其他用户不需要
So that's something that's less for the user to understand.
用户不需要知道那么多
They don't have to know anything about what's going on under the hood.
不需要知道引擎下面发生了什么
And they could think of the SLList class as just a magical black box.
他们可以把 SLList 类看作一个神奇的黑匣子
They don't have to know about the naked recursive data structure inside.
不需要知道内部裸露的递归数据结构
Likewise, you're welcome to change any private method or private constructor or private variable that you want.
同样你也可以根据需要更改任何私有方法、私有构造函数或私有变量
It's your own personal implementation.
这是你自己的实现
So if it's marked private, it's not something else someone is going to rely on.
如果被标记为 private，它就不是其他人要依赖的东西
So as an analogy, in a car, we have some public parts.
打个比方，我们在车里有一些公共部件
We have the pedals in the steering wheel.
方向盘、踏板...
We have the idea that there is an accelerator pedal and a brake pedal.
有一个油门踏板和一个刹车踏板
One should speed me up.
一个用来加速
One should slow me down.
一个用来减速
The steering wheel, when I turn it that way,
当我这样转动方向盘时
I should be turning that direction.
应该转向这个方向
And then there's a bunch of private details to the car.
这辆车还有一堆私密的细节
So you may have a fuel line that
可能有一条燃料管
is able to carry liquid fuel from one part of the car to the other, but some cars don't have that.
能够将液体燃料从车的一个部分运送到另一个部分，但有些车没有
There is no notion of fuel.
有些没有燃料的概念
You just have a battery and electric motor.
只有电池和电动马达
So those are private details you can manipulate however you want because the user does not think about them.
你可以随意操作这些私人细节，因为用户不会考虑它们
They don't think, oh, I need to worry about fuel injection.
他们不会想：“我需要担心燃油喷射”
It's not on their menu.
不在他们考虑范围内
Now, despite the term access control--
尽管有“访问控制”这个词
people use that to refer to the public, private, and so forth feature in Java--
人们用它来指代 Java 中 public、private 等特性
it has nothing to do with protection against people trying to do bad stuff with your code
但它并不能避免有人对你的代码做坏事
because, if they have access to your source code,
因为如果他们能访问到你的源代码
they can do whatever they want.
他们就可以为所欲为
So that's not it has to do with.
访问控制无法避免
It is, instead, simply a way to signal to other programmers you should not use this,
相反，访问控制只是告诉其他程序员你不希望别人使用它
and it's a soft restriction by the compiler
这是编译器的软限制
so you can't mess with it.
你不能弄乱它
Now, there's actually another side point I should mention here,
实际上我应该在这强调另一点
that if you make something public in Java, the expectation is that you will never, ever remove it.
如果你在 Java 中将一些东西设为 public，就意味着你期望永远不会删除它
In much the same way that if you sit down in a car that has no steering wheel,
就像你坐在一辆没有方向盘的车里
you're not going to want to drive it.
你不会想开它的
I mean, yes, it is technically possible there would be some joystick, but it's just not what people expect.
从技术上讲可能会有一些操纵杆，但这不是人们所期望的
So in the case of Java classes,
在 Java 类的情况下
whenever you provide a public method,
每当你提供 public 方法时
you're basically announcing to the world that they will have access to that method forever.
你基本上是在向全世界宣布，这些方法永远可以使用
So private is stuff you can mess with that the user never needs to know about.
所以 private 是你可以随意摆弄但用户不知道的东西
Public is something that should stay true forever.
public 是应该永远保持不变的东西
Otherwise, we break backwards compatibility with other code.
否则我们会破坏与其他代码的向后兼容性
So that's one thing we can do is make pieces of our class private.
所以我们可以将类的这部分设为 private
So another little augmentation we can do is nesting a class.
我们还可以做的另一个小小的增强是嵌套类
So if we think about this IntNode class--
考虑一下这个 IntNode 类
I accidentally closed the file, possibly, here it is--
我不小心把文件关了...
so here is IntNode.
这就是 IntNode
So it is possible to take this away and say IntNode it really should not be its own class, like file.
可以把这些去掉，IntNode 不应该是单独的类
It shouldn't be it's own Java file because it's really a feature of an SLList.
不应该是单独的 Java 文件，实际上它是 SLList 的一个特性
So in Java, it's pretty natural that you can just take a class
在 Java 中很自然地你可以操作一个类
and move it inside of another class declaration.
将其移动到另一个类的声明中
And if I compile this, it will work just fine.
这个会编译成功的
So you can move classes inside of other classes.
你可以将类移动到其他类的内部
This will be the boss, and this is now a subordinate class,
这个是 boss，这个现在是从属类
though in Java the term people use is nested class.
Java 中人们使用的术语是嵌套类
So this is a nested class definition.
这是嵌套类的定义
I made it public, but you can actually also make it private.
我把它设为 public，但实际上你也可以把它设为 private
It is typical, but not always,
人们经常这样做
that what you'll do is put the nested class definitions up top and everything else below.
把嵌套类的定义放在上面，其他放在下面
But you can do whatever you want.
但你可以随意放置
So typically, I'll take this and move it down here.
只是通常情况下，我会把它移到这里
But it just depends on the convention of the environment you're working on.
这取决于你工作环境的习惯
So if you work for a company that always puts nested classes up front, do that.
如果你的公司习惯将嵌套类放在前面，就这样做
If you're working for a project team
如果你工作的项目团队
where you always put it at the end do that instead.
总是把它发放到最后，就那样做
Doesn't matter what order.
顺序无关紧要
So why?
为什么呢？
What's good about a nested class?
嵌套类有什么好处？
Well, they're useful whenever a class you're declaring doesn't stand on its own,
只要你定义的类不是独立存在的，这就很有用
whenever it's obvious that an IntNode is really just something used by an SLList and only SLLists.
显然，IntNode 只被 SLList 所使用
It's subordinate to the SLList class in some way.
它在某种程度上从属于 SLList 类
Now, occasionally, you will actually want an external program to be able to
偶尔你可能想让一个外部程序能够
make instances of IntNodes or directly manipulate them in some way.
创建 IntNode 的实例或以某种方式直接操作它们
So I could, for example--
举个例子
this would be very strange behavior--
这个行为会很奇怪
but I could do something like public IntNode getFrontNode,
这样 public IntNode getFrontNode()
in which case I really need the IntNode class to be public
在这种情况下，我确实需要 IntNode 类是 public
so that someone is actually able to make IntNodes or have references to them.
这样其他人就能够创建 IntNode 实例或拥有它们的引用
But in a class like this where the user never needs to even know about IntNode,
但是在这样的类中，用户甚至不需要知道 IntNode
we can make this private.
我们可以设为 private
So in this way, what this says is that IntNodes can never be made by an external user.
这种方式意味着 IntNode 永远不能由外部用户创建
So if we have SLList user, you could not make an IntNode.
SLList 的使用者无法创建 IntNode
But we're kind of splitting hairs.
我们有点吹毛求疵
This is probably getting a little boring for a video.
可能让视频有点无聊
But the basic rule of thumb is, if nobody else ever needs an IntNode reference, make it private.
但基本的经验是，如果没人需要 IntNode 的引用，就将其设为 private
Now, to go one level deeper--
继续深入了解
and I don't want to get too much into minutiae of Java--
我其实不想过多地讨论 Java 的细节...
but if it is the case that the nested class--
但是如果嵌套类是这样...
so I said make this private if no external class uses IntNodes, OK--
如果没有外部类使用 IntNodes 就把它设为 private 对吧
so this is yet another thing like that.
还有一件类似的事情
If the IntNode class never uses any detail of the SLList class,
如果 IntNode 类从不使用 SLList 类的任何详细信息
if the nested class never needs to look out,
如果嵌套类从不需要的话
you can add the word static here.
可以在这里加上 static
Now, that probably seems like this word static pops up in a lot of strange places.
好像 static 出现在了好多奇怪的地方
I'm not going to go into right now why I decided to use the word static,
我现在不打算深入讨论为什么我决定使用 static
but you can imagine this keyword could be never looks outwards.
但你可以想象，这个关键词永远不会向外看
But it's not.
其实不是这些
It's static.
是 static
And what that means is that the IntNode class,
这意味着 IntNode 类
I could not write a method here that uses first.
我不能在这编写使用 first 的方法
That would not be allowed.
这是不允许的
So since this is no class, if you look at it,
因为这不是类，仔细看一下
it has its own item, its own next constructor,
它有自己的 item、next 和构造函数
but never does it try and use any of SLList's stuff--
但是它从来没有使用任何 SLList 的东西
none of its methods, none of its constructors, none of its variables.
没用它的方法，没用它的构造函数，没用它的变量
So we can make it static.
所以可以将它设为 static
Now, what good is that?
这有什么好处呢？
Well, it gives you a tiny little bit of memory savings for each IntNode.
它可以为每个 IntNode 节省一点点内存
And you can look in the book for a little more details on that.
你可以在书里找到更多关于这方面的细节
But the basic idea is simply that a nested class which is static cannot access any of the outer class's stuff.
但其基本思想很简单，即 static 嵌套类不能访问外部类的任何内容
Now, I'm sure that I pushed you to the limit of the amount of syntax that you can fit in your brain without any practice,
现在我已经把在不经过练习的情况下，你能接受的最大数量的语法传授给你了
so don't fret this too much.
别太担心
This is something you'll get a chance to explore a little bit in project 1.
项目1中你有机会自行探索
And at the risk of making this lecture even a little more boring and a little more minute,
冒着让这节课程变得更无聊的风险
I will make the very minor note that,
我再做一个次要说明
whenever you make a nested class private, these access modifiers no longer really matter.
当你将嵌套类设为 static 时，这些修饰符就不再重要了
But not an important Java detail.
这些 Java 细节不重要
So those are a couple of more improvements we could basically make to our SLList class.
以上就是我们对 SLList 类进行的更多改进
We can make this class a private static nested class,
我们可以设置一个 private static 的嵌套类
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
and we can make the first variable private.
还可以将 first 变量设为 private